Guide to the Nancy Colberg research collection on Wallace Stegner 1942-1996 1942-1996
Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
- Miscellaneous published materials by and about Wallace Stegner, 1942-1996; 3
  - Obituaries and tributes: (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Montana Magazine of Western History, (Autumn 1993)
      (Autumn 1993), 9 essays, p. 52-76
    - San Francisco Review of Books, (May/June 1993)
      18 (May/June 1993), p. 35-36
    - Outside, (September 1993)
      (September 1993), p. 64-68, 137-139
  - Two articles by Page Stegner, Wallace's son, December 1985; January-February 1990 (Box-folder 6/5)
    in California, December 1985 and National Parks, January-February 1990
  - A collection of book promotion and collecting materials: (Box-folder 6/6)
    - "Annual bibliography of Studies in Western American Literature,", (February 1984)
      Western American Literature, 9 (February 1984), p. 332 (Stegner listings).
    - "Passing Farms: Enduring Values"
      brochure for book with quote from the foreword written by Stegner
    - "Studies in the American West", 1986
      1986, new titles by University of Utah Press with Stegner on back page
    - Yolla Bolly Press promotion for Storytellers Series, "Two Rivers" (a seven story collection) by Wallace Stegner, 1989
    - "Collecting Wallace Stegner" by Diane Peterson, (May 1995)
      Firsts: Collecting First Editions, (May 1995), p. 30-37
    - Book announcement by Red Butte Press for "Wilderness Letter" with introduction by Page Stegner, November 26, 1995
    - Brochure for appearance of Wallace Stegner as a speaker at the Intermountain Booksellers Association, (undated)
      Trade Show (undated)
    - Willow Creek Books bookmark
      (Book store owned by Nancy Colberg and her husband)
- Letters from Wallace Stegner to Nancy Colberg, January 5, 1982 - December 9, 1990; 4 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Business correspondence for selected publications of Wallace Stegner, 1943-1976; 5
  A collection of photocopied business correspondence related to specific publications of Wallace Stegner. They are arranged alphabetically by title. Included are letters from The Brandt and Brandt literary agency; publishing firms: Duell, Sloan and Pearce, Inc.; McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc.; Curtis Brown Ltd.; Meredith Press; Look Magazine; Houghton Mifflin Company; Citadel Press; Atlantic Monthly Press; Viking Press, Inc.; Horizon; Hammond, Hammond and Company Ltd.; and ancillary letters from individuals, educational institutions and law firms pertaining to these titles.
  - The Big Rock Candy Mountain: photocopies of business correspondence, February 15, 1943 - June 29, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Fire and Ice: photocopies of business correspondence, April 2, 1948 - February 24, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Gathering of Zion: photocopies of business correspondence, January 15, 1963 - March 15, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Mormon Country: photocopies of business correspondence, January 27, 1943 - March 31, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - On a Darkling Plain: photocopies of business correspondence, October 13, 1948 - August 18, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - One Nation: photocopies of business correspondence, September 9, 1943 - April 16, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Preacher and the Slave: photocopies of business correspondence, November 17, 1949 - April 12, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Second Growth: photocopies of business correspondence, July 15, 1946 - January 3, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Shooting Star: photocopies of business correspondence, January 17 - July 5, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Wolf Willow: photocopies of business correspondence, May 29, 1962 - November 28, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Women on the Wall: photocopies of business correspondence, March 11, 1947 - April 22, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 11)